Title: Introduction to Categorical Logic.

Abstract: In this two-talk series, we will learn about the basics of categorical logic, an area of mathematics which is has overlap with algebraic geometry, pure logic and formalisation of mathematics, but is interesting to study in its own right. 

In the first talk, we will learn about the anatomy of logical theories (syntax) and how to interpret them in categories with enough structure (semantics). 

In the second talk, we will take a closer look at geometric logic and Grothendieck topoi.

— Finn Klein