L-functions are an essential tool of modern number theory, and a source of striking and mysterious mathematics. In these talks we will discuss some of the history of their development, and their applications to algebraic and analytic number theory. 

Topics will include (time permitting): the Riemann hypothesis, Dirichlet's theorem on primes in arithmetic progressions, the class number formula, the Birch and Swinnerton-Dyer conjecture, and the general ideas of the Langlands' philosophy. 

No prior experience with an L-function will be assumed.