Title: A multi-valued perspective on Hilbert's 21st problem.

Abstract: Hilbert, in his famous address of the ICM at the turn of the twentieth
century, posed a problem on Fuchsian ODEs and monodromy now
known as Hilbert’s 21st problem. The history of this problem, especially
in the original one variable case, is complicated. Rather than
going down this rabbit hole, I will describe some of the beautiful mathematics
that inspired and has spun out of this problem. Topics that we
will touch on include character varieties, circular polygons, Del Pezzo
surfaces, isomonodromic deformations, Painlevé equations, singular integral
equations and special functions.

The first seminar will be focused on the regular singular setting. In
the second, we may turn to the irregular singular or q-difference setting.

— Pieter Roffelsen