Title: Introduction to translation surfaces.

Abstract: How can billiards help us find shortest paths in the space of Riemann surfaces?
What does this have to do with shuffling pieces of intervals?

Translation surfaces and their moduli spaces will allow us to answer these questions.

Gluing opposite sides of a parallelogram together gives a torus. A translation surface is a surface obtained by identifying sides of more complicated polygons by translations.

I will give an introduction to translation surfaces and their moduli space.
We will discuss dynamics on both of these objects and their connections.

— Thomas Fils